English subtitles are available
钱总
I am no longer
我现在已经
Mr. Qian anymore.
不是什么钱总了
Just call me Qian Peng.
你叫我钱蓬就行
I heard from Feifei,
我听菲菲说了
that you have already left the company.
你已经离开公司了
Isn't that all thanks to you?
那还不是拜你所赐啊
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
I used to be the Vice President of Sales,
我本来是销售副总
a regional leader, so to speak.
也算是一方诸侯
But now the company's under investigation.
可现在公司被查封了
I invested all my savings,
我把所有的积蓄
into the company's financial products.
全购买公司理财产品了
Now, I can't withdraw a single cent.
现在一分钱都拿不出来
My ten years of hard work,
我十几年的努力
have now been wiped out completely.
现在已经全部清零了
Do you know that?
你知道吗
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
We must have a conscience in life.
咱做人得有良心啊
I was so good to you before.
我以前对你多好
I treated you better
我对所有销售
than any other salespeople.
都没有对你好
You know that?
你知道吗
I took on so much pressure
我顶着多大压力
to get you into the sales department.
把你弄到销售部
I reserved the best listings,
我把所有最好的房源
just for you.
都留给你
So, you could make sales and earn money.
让你开单去挣钱
I even let you come late and leave early
也是我让你晚来早走
to pick up your kid,
去接孩子
and attend training classes.
上什么培训班
But look at you now.
可你现在倒好
You've climbed high
你攀上高枝了
and turned around to ruin me.
反手把我给毁了
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
You can't be so vicious to me.
你不能对我这么恶毒啊
Mr. Qian.
钱总
I'm trying to save you.
我是在挽救你
If I don't speak up.
如果我不说出来
How many families will end up bankrupt?
会有多少家庭破家破产
Especially the elderly ones.
尤其那些老人
They are our long-time owners.
都是我们的老业主
Our old clients.
老客户
What did they do wrong?
他们做错什么了
You're an adult now.
你是成年人了
You should be accountable
你应该为你的行为
for your actions.
付出代价
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
I speak to you with emotion,
我跟你讲情
and you respond with logic, right?
你跟我讲理是吗
You've caused my current situation.
你给我害成现在这样
Just want a kind word from you.
我就想听你说句好话
Is that too much to ask?
不行吗
Just say something nice to me.
你就跟我说句好话
I'm sorry, Mr. Qian.
对不起 钱总
I have nothing more to say.
我没什么好说的
Take care of yourself.
你好自为之吧
My aunt has now gone back to our hometown.
我大姑现在回老家了
Living at home feels like
我在家里过得
I'm on vacation,
就跟度假似的
with an umbrella over my head.
头上支把伞
It's like I'm camping out.
直接就露营了
Right now,
我现在
I eat whatever I want.
想吃什么吃什么
I lie down whenever I want.
我想躺着就躺着
No one tells me I'm unhealthy anymore.
再也没人说我不健康了
Is that right?
是吧
Not listening to the elders,
不听老人言
living happily for years.
快活好几年
Li Lin.
李临
Can you speak properly?
你有话能不能好好说
What's with your attitude?
你这什么态度啊
Wait a second.
你等一下啊
What attitude?
我什么态度
I've always had this attitude.
我一向就是这个态度
I'm saying all this for your own good.
我说的这些是为了你好
You're doing this for my good?
你为我好吗
Is this really for my good?
你这叫为我好吗
Can you speak with your conscience?
你能不能凭良心说
No, no, no.
不不不
Am I doing this for myself?
难道是我为我自己吗
For myself?
为了我自己吗
Isn't this doing it for yourself?
这不叫为你自己吗
This is really strange.
我这 真是好奇怪
Look.
你看
Didn't I say there were mosquitoes?
我说是不是有蚊子
Just spray a bit, so what?
就喷一下 怎么
It's not toxic.
它没毒啊
I said I don't want it.
我说了我不要
But you insisted on it.
你非得要
Is this how you do things?
有你这样的吗
Fine, then I won't care, okay?
行 那我不管了 好吗
I won't care anymore.
我不管了
Whether you care or not.
爱管不管
Don't care for the rest of your life.
这辈子都别管
Mom.
妈
Dad.
爸
She...
她
This is really ridiculous.
真的是莫名其妙
Really.
真的
What's going on here?
这这 怎么回事
None of your business. You...
没你事 你
Go do your homework!
你先做功课去吧
She went out.
她出去了
Look at this.
你看看
In the middle of the night.
大半夜的
Alright, go do your homework.
行了 你做功课去
I'll go find her.
我去找她
What's going on?
怎么回事啊
What's there to argue about?
有什么好吵吵的
First, let's talk about you, Dad.
先来说你 爸
My mom is pregnant.
我妈她是孕妇
She can't get upset, you know?
不能生气 你知道吗
And what about gentlemanly conduct?
还绅士风度
Where's the civility and manners?
文明礼貌呢
Normally, aren't you
你平时不
always defending my mom?
挺护着我妈的吗
What's the matter with you?
怎么回事啊你
Dropping the ball at the crucial moment.
关键时刻掉链子
Stop it.
别说了你
And as for you, Mom,
再来说你 妈
don't think just because you are pregnant,
别觉得自己是个孕妇
you can do whatever you want.
你想干吗就干吗
Do you think that you don't have
你自己就一点问题
problems at all?
都没有吗
Think about it.
你好好想想
Dad's doing it for your own good.
我爸肯定是为了你好呀
Right?
对不对
I think you've been
我看你呀
acting like you've swallowed a bomb.
最近就是吃炸药了
waiting to explode at any time.
一点就着
If you scare
你要是吓着
Little Grape, what then?
小葡萄怎么办
Can you take responsibility?
负得起这个责任吗
It's such a serious issue.
多么严重的问题
Think it through.
你好好想一想
Reflect on it.
反思反思
It takes two to tango.
一个巴掌拍不响
You should reflect too.
你也反思
Still making me worry.
还得让我操心
I'm worried sick.
急死我了
Do you know how worried I am?
你知道我多担心吗
Try again in a different way.
换种方式 再来一次
Where could they go?
你说人能去哪儿啊
It's so late.
这么晚了
There's no one here.
这没人哪
Are they really fighting?
他俩真吵架呀
Your dad dares to fight with your mom?
你爸敢跟你妈吵
Really.
真的
Trust me, really.
你信我 真的
They were quarreling fiercely.
吵得可凶了
I was stunned at the time. I said...
我当时都蒙了 我说
Oh my god, my dad
天哪 我老爸
Dare to talk to my mom like that?
这 敢这么跟我妈说话
Seriously.
真是
At the time, my mom left.
当时 我妈先走的
and my dad ran after her.
我爸追出去了
Where else could they go?
不然能去哪儿啊 他俩
It's so late at night.
这大晚上的
Where else can they go?
还能去哪儿啊
Exactly.
就说嘛
Look at these two.
你说这两个人
They really cause so much worry.
真让人不省心
Is that the one?
那个是吗
Which one?
哪个
Look over there. Is that a person?
你看那儿 那是人
No, it's not.
不是
Smells so good.
好香啊
I'm getting hungry.
我都饿了
Yeah, smells great.
是挺香的
Come on, clink glasses.
走 碰一下
Alright.
好
Three bottles.
三瓶啊
Boss, add two more squid skewers.
老板 再加两串鱿鱼
You've been craving this long, right?
是不是想这口好久了
Feels like a lifetime ago.
上辈子的事
Here, your skewers are ready.
来 你的肉串好了
Take this flashlight stick.
把这手 手电棒子
Don't go over there.
别过去
Is it tasty?
好吃吗
It's okay.
还行
Are you happy?
开心吗
Is this fun for you two?
你们两个有意思吗
Just for some barbecue,
为了吃顿烧烤
you argue and lie to the kid.
吵架骗孩子
What did Auntie say?
大姑怎么说的
How should we live healthily?
养生应该怎么做
This barbecue...
这烧烤
and this...
还有这个
can you eat this?
这能吃吗
No.
不能
And it's so late already,
而且都这么晚了
you're still eating unhealthy things?
还吃这些不健康的
Is this right?
这对吗
No, it's not.
不对
Speak up.
说
Were you two
你们两个是不是
planning this for a long time?
蓄谋已久
No.
不是
Yes.
是
Just now, weren't the two of us
刚才我们俩
arguing just now?
还不吵架呢吗
Pretending? Didn't we agree
装 不都说好了吗
that the three of us
咱们三个
would go out for barbecue
一起出来吃烧烤
to eat and then air out the smell?
吃完还散散味
Why didn't you take me?
为什么不带我呀
This... this is...
这 这不是
We couldn't sleep at night,
晚上睡不着
and wanted to go out on a date
想跟你爸出来
with your dad.
浪漫一下吗
With me, it's not romantic, right?
有我就不浪漫了 是吗
It is.
浪
But,
但
Isn't it a bit different?
它不是不太一样吗
He Lu.
何璐
Are your parents like this too?
你爸妈也这样吗
I don't know.
我不知道
We're all unnecessary.
我们都是多余的
Twenty more minutes
还有二十分钟
and I'll be leaving this company.
我就要离开这家公司了
If Mr. Yu doesn't see me off,
于总要是不送我出去
I'll let the whole world know,
我就让全世界都知道
that you used me and dumped me.
是你对我始乱终弃
Stop, Huang Sisi.
别 黄思思
Let's clarify what that means first.
咱先说清楚这话
What do you mean by 'used and dumped'?
什么叫始乱终弃呀
From the start until now,
咱们俩从开始到现在
have we ever messed around?
咱们乱过吗
Nineteen more minutes.
还有十九分钟
Your contract with Blue Ocean
你跟蓝海的劳动合同
will automatically terminate.
就自动解除了
Let's part on good terms, okay?
咱们好聚好散 好不好
These three years
咱们这三年呢
we've worked together as colleagues.
同事一场
You've made many contributions
应该说你为公司
to the company.
做了很多的贡献
But Blue Ocean hasn't treated you badly.
但是蓝海也没亏待你
and offered you great terms.
给了你很好的待遇
I even wrote you
我也给你写了一篇
a good recommendation letter.
非常完美的推荐信
Let's part on good terms.
咱们好聚好散
And your next job
再说你下家
is already lined up, right?
不是找好了吗
You're going to Xinmiao.
去新苗
Right?
对吧
Let's not tangle any further.
咱们就不要再纠缠了吧
Where I go next,
我后面要去哪里
isn't things Mr. Yu needs to worry about.
就不劳于先生费心了
Fine.
行
Just go.
走就好
But,
但是呢
I still have some advice for you.
我还得给你个建议
You see, our city
你说 咱们这个城市
is so small.
这么小
Right?
对吧
This circle is small too.
这个圈子它也小
Why don't you switch to another city?
你不如换个城市
I promise, with all my ability,
我保证尽我所有的能力
to help you find a good company
我帮你找一家好公司
and negotiate good terms for you.
帮你谈一个好的待遇
How does that sound?
你看好不好
Why?
凭什么
Why should I be the one to leave?
凭什么要离开的人
Why does it have to be me?
就得是我呢
Why do I have to leave this city
我还得离开这个城市
and
我还得离开
the network I've cultivated for years?
我深耕多年的圈子
Yu Hai.
于海
You...
你
You don't actually
不会真把你们俩
blame your divorce
离婚的锅
on me, do you?
扣在我身上了吧
No, no way.
没有
Absolutely not.
那绝对没有
My divorce is my own issue.
我离婚是我自己的事
It has nothing
跟你
to do with you at all.
一点关系都没有
The reason I'm advising you this way
我之所以这么劝你
is really for your own good
我真的是为了你好
dear.
妹妹
With me, you're already
你在我这儿
a content director.
已经是内容总监了
At Xinmiao, at most you'll be
你到新苗 你顶多屈尊
a deputy director.
你就做个副总监嘛
Right? I know Xinmiao's
对吧 新苗的情况
situation very well.
我非常了解
Xu Meng'an is firmly
许梦安在那儿
established there.
坐得稳稳的
Plus, she's very skilled.
而且她的能力又那么强
It's hard to shine at Xinmiao.
你到了新苗
You're unlikely to get ahead.
你是很难出头的
Why not just switch cities?
咱不如换个城市吗
Right?
对不对
The sea is vast for fish to leap.
海阔凭鱼跃
The sky is high for birds to fly.
天高任鸟飞
How wonderful.
多好
Talking for so long,
说了那么半天
going around in such a big circle.
绕这么一大圈
I really thought
我还真以为
you were doing it for my good.
你是为我好呢
Turns out it was for
原来是为了
your old classmate, Xu Meng'an.
你的老同学许梦安
A classmate working
一个在对手公司
at a rival company
工作的同学
is more important to you than me.
在你心里都比我重要
Huang Sisi.
黄思思
Don't talk.
你别说话
Actually,
我其实
I haven't decided
还真没决定
if I'm really going to Xinmiao.
一定要去新苗
But at the award ceremony that day
但那天在颁奖礼上
I noticed your classmate
我发现你同学
was pregnant.
怀孕了
It's an opportunity.
这是个机会
So,
所以呢
this deputy director position
我的这个副总监
it's just temporary.
只是暂时的
Understand?
明白了吗
You, wipe your eyes clean,
你 擦干净眼睛
and watch closely.
好好看着
Whether I have you or not,
我有没有你
I can still get things done.
都能成事
Why are you like a loach
你怎么就跟个泥鳅似的
slipping into every crack you see?
见个缝你就往里钻呢
Fine.
好
Let's see
那就看看
how you fare without my Blue Ocean platform.
你离开我蓝海平台
Let's see what you're really worth.
你到底有几斤几两
I'd like to see as well
我也想看看
how Blue Ocean does without Huang Sisi.
蓝海没了黄思思
How much weight will it lose?
还能剩几斤几两
Fine.
好
Hello, are you Chen Wanzhen?
您好 陈婉真是吗
That's me.
是我
Is it my turn?
到我了吗
Yes, it is.
是的
Excuse me,
请问一下
who will be interviewing me?
一会儿面试我的
Which department head?
是哪个部门的主管
Our boss.
我们的大老板
Zhou Yao.
周耀
He asked to interview you personally.
他点名要亲自面试你
Mr. Zhou?
周耀总
I'm also surprised.
我也很意外
This is the first time that Mr. Zhou
这还是我们周耀总
has personally interviewed
第一次亲自面试
a candidate of your level.
你这个职级的候选人
Please follow me.
那您跟我来吧
Come in.
进来
Mr. Zhou, Ms. Chen is here.
周总 陈女士到了
Wendy.
温蒂
You're finally back.
你终于回来了
Hello, Mr. Zhou.
周总 你好
No one has called me Wendy in a long time.
好久没有人叫我温蒂了
Only you call me that.
只有你这么叫我
Can I be like everyone else?
那我能跟别人一样吗
Come, sit.
来 坐
You have my contact information,
你有我的联络方式
so why did you still
你为什么还要给
send your resume to HR?
人力资源投简历呢
I wanted to see
我是想看看
if I could get into Yaohui Co.
是不是能靠自己的能力
through my own abilities.
敲开耀辉的大门
But I heard from a headhunter,
可我从猎头那儿
that not only did you knock on my door,
得到消息
you knocked on several others' doors too.
你不仅敲了我的门
You've even had a round of interviews.
你还敲了好几家的门
You've had one round of interviews.
你都面试一轮了
Yaohui Co. is always my first choice.
耀辉是我永远的首选
Actually
其实
I just retook my professional
我是刚刚重考了
qualification exams.
执业资格
I don't know
我不知道
what my worth is
我在这个行业
in this industry right now.
现在是几斤几两
So, you didn't want to come to me.
所以你不想来找我
Afraid that your abilities aren't enough
怕万一自己能力不够
and that I'd owe you a favor.
欠我人情
Wendy.
温蒂呀
We graduated at twenty-five
我们两个二十五岁毕业
and joined investment banking together.
同期进投行
We worked together for seven years.
在一起共事了七年
Investment is all about knowing people.
投资就是识人
How could I not know your capabilities?
我能不清楚你的能力吗
It's me who lacks confidence now.
是我自己没有自信了
After all, I left this industry
毕竟离开这个行业
for so many years.
这么多年
This doesn't sound like
这可不像
something you'd say.
你说出来的话呀
I don't know what you've been through
我不知道这些年
all these years.
你都经历了什么
But,
但是
never underestimate yourself.
永远不要低估自己
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
谢谢周总
This... This is my resume.
这个 这是我的简历
This is what I've been doing on recently.
这是我最近做的
Huaying Real Estate Co.
华謃地产
The financial report and my summary.
财务报告和我的总结
Take a look at it.
你看一下
This isn't urgent.
这个不着急
Wendy.
温蒂
I've been waiting for you lately.
我最近一直在等你
Just waiting for today.
就等着今天
For this moment to happen.
这一幕的发生
You are knocking on my office door
主动敲开我办公室的门
standing before me and saying,
站到我的面前跟我说
Zhou Yao
周耀
I want to return to my old profession.
我要重新回到老本行
You must give me
你必须给我
a job.
提供一份工作
This is the real Chen Wanzhen.
这才是真正的陈婉真
Alright.
好啊
Zhou Yao
周耀
I am now
我现在要
returning to my old profession.
重回我的老本行了
You must
你必须
provide me with a job.
给我提供一份工作
Chen Wanzhen.
陈婉真
Congratulations.
恭喜你
You're hired.
入职了
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
谢谢周总
Let's start our first
那我们开始第一次
official report.
正式的汇报
Back when Wanzhen
婉真她当初
suddenly asked for a divorce,
突然间提出来要离婚
I wanted to keep the peace.
我为了息事宁人
So, I let Huang Sisi leave quickly.
让黄思思尽快走
I didn't sign
我就没跟她签
the non-compete agreement with her.
这个竞业禁止协议
Why are you telling me this?
你跟我说这干吗
Is she really coming to Xinmiao?
她是确定要来新苗了吗
Yes, it's confirmed.
确定了
She already knows that you're pregnant.
她已经知道你怀孕了
And her terms with Mr. Zhang
而且跟老张的条件
seem to be mostly agreed upon.
应该是谈得差不多了
She's heading to your company.
她到你们公司去
First, take on this deputy director role.
先做这副总监
It's just a transitional phase.
那就是个过渡
Anyone with eyes can see it.
明眼人都看得出来
It's obviously aiming
那就是奔着你
for your position.
这位置去的
Well,
那
let them come in.
就来呗
We can't just sit and wait to be defeated.
咱不能坐以待毙吧
I've thought of a way
我给你想好了
out for you.
一条出路啊
What way out?
什么出路啊
Switch jobs.
跳槽
Come over to my Blue Ocean.
你到我蓝海来啊
Can you stop messing around?
你能不能别闹了
No.
不是
Let me tell you.
我跟你讲
Don't let Mr. Zhang know
你千万别让老张知道
that you met with me today.
你今天找我
Are you seriously trying to poach me?
是真的要挖我啊
After all he's done to you.
他都对你那样了
Are you out of your mind?
你是不是二啊你
You're the one who's out of your mind!
你才二呢
You're still defending him?
你 你还护着他呀你
Just because you're pregnant,
就冲你怀了孕
he wants to bring Huang Sisi
他要把这黄思思
into your company.
弄到你们公司去
That alone is wronging you.
这一点他就对不住你
Just for that,
就冲这个
I'll dig him out from under you.
那我就挖他墙角了
What do you say?
怎么着
I'll poach his people before his eyes.
我当他面挖他墙角
We can't just take this crap
咱不能在他公司
in his company.
受这气吧
I won't agree to this!
我不答应啊
Yu Hai.
于海
I'm pregnant.
我怀孕了
As a company president,
你作为一个公司老总
this isn't a wise choice.
做这样的选择不明智的
Even though we're old classmates.
就算咱俩是老同学
you don't need to get this worked up.
你也用不着这么激动
No, no, no, no, no.
别别 别别别
The reason I'm trying to poach you
我之所以挖你啊
not just because you are my old classmate.
不只因为你是我老同学
It's also because
还因为
I value
我看重
your value in the workplace.
你在职场中的价值
Mr. Zhang doesn't understand that,
老张都不了解
but I do.
我了解
You just had a baby, right?
你不就生个孩子吗
It's only about a hundred days or so.
百十来天的事
I, Yu Hai, can wait.
我于海等得起
You're really that loyal?
你这么仗义吗
In my mind,
在我心里边
you truly understand content.
你是真正懂内容的
As for me,
我呢
I understand the market.
懂市场
I understand operations.
懂运营
If we work together,
咱俩在一起
we'd be a perfect match.
那才叫珠联璧合呢
All these years,
你这些年
everything you've done...
干的所有事
I've seen it all.
我都看在眼里了
It's not the first time
我这不是
I've tried to poach you, right?
第一次挖你了吧
Again and again,
一而再 再而三
over and over.
三而四 四而五的
You have to give me some credit, right?
你得给我点面子吧
Thanks a lot,
我谢谢你啊
but I really can't agree.
但我还真答应不了
To be honest,
说实话
Mr. Zhang, these past years,
老张这些年啊
has actually been quite good to me.
其实对我挺好的
He's anxious now,
他现在这么焦虑
partly because of me.
其实也有我的原因
I can't just because of
那我不能因为
a moment of instability,
一时的不稳定
deny all the care he's shown me
就否定了他这么多年
over the years, right?
对我的关照吧
And to say something in spite
再说句置气的话啊
if Xu Meng'an decides to leave.
我许梦安要走的话
Of course, it's because I want to leave.
肯定那是我自己想走
I won't be forced out by anyone.
绝对不能被别人挤对走
Don't you think so?
你说是不是
But I appreciate your trust.
但你这份信任
I get it.
我心领了
No, but,
不是 那
Huang Sisi will be joining
黄思思过两天
your company in a few days.
就到你们公司了
What will you do?
你怎么办
Just,
就
let it be.
凉拌呗
You're something else.
你真行
I really admire you.
我服了你了真是
You see, your issues
你说你的事
are making me sweat.
把我急一脑门子汗
Sandy!
森蒂
So quickly sorted everything out?
这么快整理好了
Take a look.
你看一看
Is there anything else
还有什么地方
that needs to be added?
需要补充的
The comments are very detailed,
注释得很详细
and very comprehensive.
也很全面
You've worked hard.
你辛苦了
It's nothing.
没事
Let me know if you have any issues.
有什么问题随时告诉我
Wendy.
温蒂
Do you know about mother and baby brands?
母婴品牌你了解吗
Of course I do.
当然了解啊
After all, I am
我毕竟是
a mother of two children.
两个孩子的母亲
Moreover, when I was studying
而且呢 我读
for my MBA,
工商管理硕士的时候
I also wrote a paper about
也写过关于
this industry.
这个行业的论文
Good.
正好
Wendy's related report.
温蒂做的相关报告
Let's have Wendy join this team.
让温蒂加入这个组吧
No problem.
没问题
Meeting at ten o'clock.
十点钟开会
No.
不是
Why are you still sleeping?
你怎么还睡上了
Pregnant women.
孕妇
Need rest.
需要休息
Let me tell you something,
我跟你说个事啊
I guarantee,
保证
you'll be wide awake instantly.
你马上就精神了
Huang Sisi is coming.
黄思思要来了
You knew?
你知道了
Her contract with Blue Ocean has expired.
她跟蓝海的合同到期了
Why didn't you give me a heads-up?
你不跟我通个气
This puts me in a very passive position.
搞得我很被动啊
But this is such a big deal.
不是 这么大的事
Why are you acting like
你怎么还跟个
it's no big deal?
没事人似的
I'm anxious on the inside, okay?
我在内心焦虑呢 好吗
I didn't even know she
我也不知道她
would come so soon.
这么快就要来啊
Maybe it's because
估计可能是
she found out I'm pregnant.
知道我怀孕了吧
Do you think
你说会不会是
it was Mr. Zhang who told her?
老张告诉她的
It doesn't matter anymore.
不重要了
As the director, I'm
本总监现在
very upset.
很伤心
So, what do you plan to do?
那你打算怎么办
What else can I do?
还能怎么办啊
Just face it calmly.
坦然面对呗
When she arrives
她来了
you go on vacation.
你休假去了
And when you come back,
等你再回来
There might really be no place for you.
可能就真没你位置了
Each new generation excels the last.
长江后浪推前浪嘛
So, the old waves
那前浪
just die on the beach.
就死在沙滩上呗
Your attitude is not right.
你这态度不行啊
This is way too negative.
这也太消极了
You come without a solution,
你不带着解决方案来
and yet you stress out a pregnant woman,
还对着一个孕妇
spreading anxiety here.
在这儿渲染焦虑
How can you bear this?
你情何以堪啊
Your temper has grown since pregnant.
这怀孕之后脾气见长啊
It's the hormones.
激素问题啊
Who doesn't have a bit of a bad temper?
谁还没点熊脾气了
Don't blame everything
不要什么事情
on hormones, okay?
都怪激素 好吗
I'm just here to
我这不是过来
discuss things with you, right?
跟你商量吗
No.
不是
Whose issue is this then?
这到底谁的事啊
You're not anxious, but I'm.
您不急 我在这儿急
Okay.
对呀
What's urgent and what's not?
那什么不急那什么急
Go, go, go.
去去去
I'm discussing serious matters with you.
我跟你说正事呢啊
Mr. Zhang asked me to
老张让我
do the due diligence for Huang Sisi.
可给这黄思思办尽调呢
She's starting soon.
马上就办入职
She'll be on board next week.
下周到岗
What do you think?
你说
How come she doesn't even
她怎么连个竞业协议
have a non-compete agreement?
都没有呀
You can sign one with her.
你可以跟她签呀
Of course, I'll sign with her.
那我肯定跟她签呀
For Mr. Zhang.
为了老张
I'll make sure she stays with me.
我也让她死我手里
Well done.
干得好
I've heard she's quite ruthless.
我可听说啊
She's aggressive.
她是那种狠要的女人
Do you think she
你说她
has asked Mr. Zhang for something?
是不是跟老张要了
That's for sure.
那肯定的呀
I just don't know
就是不知道
what Mr. Zhang promised her.
这老张许诺她什么了
Otherwise,
要不然
She won't accept a demotion,
她也不会甘愿降职
and come here to be a deputy director.
跑这儿来当个副总监呀
Actually, if you think about it,
其实细想想吧
this might not be such a bad thing.
这也未见得是个坏事
What's good about it?
哪儿好了
I think it's good for Mr. Zhang.
我看就对老张好
I dare say,
我敢打赌
she won't
她来这儿
stay here long.
长不了
You'd better let her stay a bit longer.
你还是让她干长一点吧
After all, I'm pregnant now,
毕竟我现在怀着孕呢
and my energy isn't what it used to be.
精力确实不如从前
I originally planned to promote
本来想着提拔一下
Ling Meichuan and Amu,
凌美川和阿木的
but both of them
结果两个人
had issues with their qualifications.
因为资历问题呢
Even if you teach hand-in-hand,
就算手把手教
it would still take a year or so.
也得个一年半载
What if something happens in the meantime?
那这中间万一出点啥事
What do we do then?
怎么弄啊
As for Huang Sisi,
这黄思思吧
her resume shows some ability,
光看着履历有点能力
but it's unclear if her ability
就不知道她这能力
is genuinely her own
到底是她自己的呢
or if it's due to platform resources.
还是平台资源给的
Resources are also a kind of ability
有资源也是一种能力呀
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
if she's truly capable,
她要真是个干将
and can help me get things in order,
能帮我把这摊事
in order,
支棱起来
I'm willing to delegate authority.
我也是愿意放权的
But I can't just throw Mr. Zhang
那毕竟不能
into a pit.
把老张扔坑里头啊
Even though Mr. Zhang
虽然老张
doing this at this time,
在这个时候干这事
is quite hurtful.
挺伤人的
But all I can do is show my understanding.
但我也只能表示理解呗
I understand as well.
我也理解
You said to handle it as usual.
你说照平时吧
I'll definitely hire you,
我肯定会给你招一个
a capable deputy director.
能干的副总监
But given your current situation,
可你现在这么个情况
aren't you afraid she'll
你就不怕她来了
take advantage of your weakness?
钻你空子
Let her take advantage then.
那就钻呗
Anyway, I've made up my mind.
反正我想好了
During my pregnancy and childbirth,
怀孕生孩子这段期间
I'll just keep a low profile.
我就韬光养晦
Whether I can return to the frontline
将来能不能回到一线
is still uncertain.
还不知道呢
If there's a real battle,
要真有一战的话
then let's fight.
那就战呗
Who's afraid of whom?
谁怕谁呀
Right.
对
I've got this.
有我呢
We're not afraid.
咱不怕
You can be afraid.
你可以怕
She'll probably come
估计她来了
and create a mess first.
就先是一通乌烟瘴气
What I'm worried about
我担心的事
is about to happen.
就要发生了
My anxiety
我的焦虑
seems to have been cured by you.
好像被你治好了
Are we still friends?
还是姐们儿吗
Mr. Zhou,
周总
this is our team's
这就是我们小组
recent research and summary
近期对各类母婴产品的
on various mother and baby products.
调研和总结
We'll leave the data collection
数据收集的工作
to Wendy.
就交给温蒂吧
Wendy,
温蒂
please follow up on this project.
那你来跟进这个项目
I'll send you the contact person
稍后我把
from the outsourcing company later.
外包公司对接人发给你
Okay.
好的
Alright, nothing else,
行 没什么事
Let's adjourn the meeting.
我们散会吧
Wendy, please stay behind.
温蒂 你留一下
Wendy,
温蒂
These small, basic tasks.
把这些零碎基础的工作
I'll leave them to you.
交给你
You won't have
你心里不会
any thoughts about it, right?
有什么想法吧
No, how could that be?
怎么会呢
I know you're just letting me
我知道你这是让我
familiarize myself with the process,
熟悉流程
and then quickly
然后让我呢
get into the role.
尽快进入角色
Even if you don't assign it to me,
你不让我做
I would still proactively apply for it.
我还会主动申请呢
t's just like playing polo.
其实就像骑马打球一样
A professional athlete
一个训练多年的
who has trained for years.
职业选手
It has muscle memory.
他是会有肌肉记忆的
But if not practiced for a long time,
但如果很久不做呢
it will become rusty.
就会生疏
So, you need to use
所以就需要用
frequent practice
频繁地练习
to awaken muscle memory.
来唤醒肌肉记忆
You just want to awaken
你就是想唤醒我的
my muscle memory.
肌肉记忆呗
Alright.
那行
From now on,
以后这些
all these small tasks
零七八碎的工作
will be mine.
都交给我
Okay, that's great.
好的 那太好了
But don't complain
但是别嫌累啊
or whine to me.
别跟我诉苦
Let's go. I wouldn't dare.
走吧 哪敢呀
Sorry,
不好意思
this is my parking spot.
这是我车位
Chen Wanzhen!
陈婉真
I'm asking you,
我问你
why are you doing this to me?
你为什么这么对我
Qian Peng, what are you trying to do?
钱蓬 你想干什么
I'm asking you!
我问你
What are you doing?
你想干什么
What's going on?
干吗呢
Who are you?
你谁啊
This has nothing to do with you.
这事跟你没关系啊
Ms. Chen, are you okay?
陈小姐 你没事吧
Let me go!
给我放开
Chen Wanzhen!
陈婉真
Chen Wanzhen, call the police!
陈婉真 报警
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
this isn't over, Chen Wanzhen!
我跟你没完 陈婉真
Don't move!
别动
Let go of me!
你给我放开
Wait here for the police!
在这儿等警察来
Chen Wanzhen, come on.
陈婉真 来
Call the police.
你报警来
Go ahead, call!
报啊
Let go of me!
你给我撒开
Is this 110?
110吗
Don't move.
你别动啊
Are you okay?
你没事吧
I really didn't expect this, Dr. Yu.
真没看出来啊 俞博士
You're not just highly educated,
你不光是学历高
you're also quite fit.
这体能也不错
Of course.
那当然了
I run a lot.
平时跑那么多步
Looks like I should
看来我平时
run even more.
还得多跑跑步
Develop
德智体美劳
in all aspects.
全面发展嘛
What happened with that guy?
那人怎么回事啊
Just a minor business dispute.
业务上的一些小纠纷
He didn't handle it well.
他也没处理好
You still need to pay attention
你还是要多注意
to your own safety.
自己的安全
Okay.
好的
Good thing you were here today.
今天得亏你在啊
Thank you, Dr. Yu.
谢谢你啊 俞医生
No problem.
没事
You're welcome.
不客气
Are you really okay?
你真没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
I'm back!
我回来啦
Sis.
大姐
Honey, I'm going to pick up Yunjie today.
老婆 我今天去接云阶
Yunjie wants to have a treat.
云阶要打打牙祭
There are wontons in the fridge.
冰箱里有馄饨
You can eat them yourself.
你自己吃啊
Meng'an.
梦安
Now that you're pregnant,
你现在怀孕了
you get hungry easily.
特别爱饿
I made wontons
我呀 把馄饨包好了
and froze them for you.
给你冻在冰箱里
You can cook them whenever you're hungry.
你饿了随时可以煮
In the wonton wrappers,
咱这馄饨皮里啊
I added eggs.
我放了鸡蛋
They're extra chewy.
特别筋道
Hello,
喂
brother-in-law.
姐夫
Is sis at home?
大姐在家呢吗
Brother-in-law, don't worry.
姐夫 你也别着急
I'll keep looking.
我再找一找
When Lilin comes back later,
然后一会儿李临回来了
I'll ask him.
我再问问他
Alright?
好呗
I'll call you if I find her.
我找着了给你打电话
We're back!
我们回来喽
Why are you back?
怎么回来了
Your precious daughter
你宝贝闺女
couldn't bear to leave you alone at home.
舍不得你一个人在家呀
I'm the best, right?
还是我好吧
Yeah, you're the best.
对 你最好了
I just called brother-in-law,
我刚才跟姐夫打电话
sis didn't go home.
大姐她没回家呀
Didn't go home?
没回家
And her phone
而且大姐电话
is not reachable now.
现在也打不通
So where did she go?
那她去哪儿了
Auntie is an adult.
大姑这么大的人了
It's not like she's missing.
不至于找不着的
Why don't you think about it again?
要不你再想想
Does she have any other friends
她在春江
in Chunjiang?
还有没有别的朋友
Let's go look for her.
咱去找找啊
Ms. Song.
宋姐
Lilin, did you get the address?
李临 地址你收到了吧
Yes, I got it.
收到了 收到了
I'm on my way.
正在去的路上
I'll be there soon.
一会儿就到
Alright, alright.
好好好
Call me if you need anything.
那有事再给我打电话哈
Okay, thank you, Ms. Song.
好嘞 谢谢你宋姐
No problem.
没事
See, I told you it's fine.
你看 我就说没事吧
She must have gone
她肯定是
to find her old foreign teacher friend.
找她外教老同学去了
She's working as a nanny now.
人去当月嫂去了
Isn't she busy enough
家里的事
with family matters,
还不够她忙的吗
serving others?
伺候别人了
I'm speechless.
服了她了
This woman...
这个姐
I have no words left.
没话说了
What are the dietary fiber requirements
孕产妇的膳食纤维
for pregnant and lactating women?
要求是什么样的呢
Now, I'd like a student to come up
现在请一位同学上来
and use the props on our table,
用我们桌上的道具
to create a meal plan
搭配出一个孕产妇
for one day for a pregnant woman,
一天的食物搭配
and explain the principles of the plan.
并且说明搭配原则
Which student
哪位同学
would like to try?
愿意上来试一下
Alright, this student here.
好 这位学员
Pregnant women
孕产妇
should base the diet on the food pyramid,
要根据膳食金字塔
balancing nutrition and taste.
搭配饮食
They need to consume
还要兼顾营养和味道
high-quality carbohydrates daily.
每天摄入优质碳水
It should be 300 to 500 grams.
应该是三百到五百克
For example, breakfast,
比如说早餐
we can eat
我们可以吃
steamed buns and millet porridge.
馒头 小米粥
Lunch, rice.
中午 米饭
Dinner, noodles.
晚上 面条
Vegetables should be consumed about
蔬菜呢 大概每天摄入
300 to 500 grams daily.
三百到五百克
Such as cucumbers, eggplants, carrots.
像黄瓜 茄子 胡萝卜
Fruits, around
水果呢 每天大概是
200 to 350 grams a day.
二百到三百五十克
High-quality protein
优质蛋白
is needed at 200 grams daily.
每天需要二百克
For breakfast, a glass of milk and eggs
早餐 一杯牛奶 鸡蛋
are essential.
是少不了的
And also,
还有
these shrimp
这个虾
are the best for high - quality protein.
是最好的优质蛋白
12,800.
一万两千八
Oh my God.
天哪
Nannies are so expensive now!
现在月嫂这么贵啊
Sis's value is definitely beyond that.
姐的价值肯定不止于此
Why are you looking at me?
你看我干吗
She stays at our place,
她在咱家
washes clothes, cooks,
不洗衣服不做饭哪
buys groceries and does the cleaning.
不买菜不打扫卫生啊
We are taking advantage.
得便宜卖乖
Got her to leave.
把人整走了
Hello,
您好
are you two looking for a nanny?
二位是找月嫂的吗
We're looking for someone.
我们找人
Everyone, please be mindful,
大家以后要注意啊
this 95% high-concentration
这种百分之九十五的
alcohol
高浓度酒精
cannot be used directly for disinfection.
是不能用来直接消毒的
You must add
必须要加入
an appropriate amount of distilled water
适量的蒸馏水
and dilute it to 75%.
稀释成百分之七十五
Only then can it be used
才能用于
for household sanitation disinfection.
家庭卫生的消毒用
Then just use this alcohol.
那直接用这种酒精
It's got a higher purity.
纯度更高
Won't it kill the bacteria
那 不把那细菌
completely?
杀得透透的呀
That won't work.
那可不行啊
Actually,
其实啊
this 95%
这种百分之九十五的
high-concentration alcohol
高浓度酒精
directly for disinfection,
直接用来消毒啊
is not very effective.
效果并不好
Because viruses and bacteria
因为啊 病毒和细菌
can't be killed
在无水的条件下
without water.
是杀不死的
Really?
真的
Yes, that's why it needs to be diluted.
是啊 所以要稀释嘛
Just listen to the big sister.
就是 听大姐的没错
Ms. Jing used to be
咱们静姐
a head nurse.
以前可是护士长
Right, right.
对对对
I've been doing this job my whole life.
我干了一辈子这个工作
Skilled work, you know.
熟练工种嘛
In the future,
咱们以后啊
we'll work as a maternity matron.
去做月嫂
Postpartum women are very weak.
产妇都很虚弱
Ensure disinfection and sterilization.
一定做好消毒杀菌工作
Everyone, come over here.
大家过来一下
I'll show you
我给你们演示一下
how to mix it.
怎么配比
Alright, come on.
好 来
Look,
你看
she's even teaching others now.
她怎么还教上别人了
Sis was a head nurse, okay?
姐是护士长好吧
Talking about disinfection,
说消毒的事
who knows it better than her?
谁能有她明白啊
Exactly.
对
Making the most of her experience.
发挥余热啊
She's needed.
那是被需要
How old are you, sis?
你多大岁数了 姐
How come after retiring
你怎么退休之后
you've learned to lie?
还学会说瞎话了呢
I didn't lie.
我没说瞎话
I really
我本来嘛
just wanted to come and learn.
就是想来学学
A maternity nurse.
母婴护理师
I never said I'd be a nanny.
也没说要当月嫂啊
But then Meng An got pregnant.
那这不梦安怀孕了吗
Meng An,
梦安
I only found out after coming here.
到了这儿我才知道
This nanny job
这个月嫂
really pays well.
挣得真不少
Anyway, you're not due yet.
反正你现在又没生呢
So, why not let me work
要不然我先干着
and get some practice?
练练手
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
Are you short of money?
你缺钱啊
You need to earn this money?
你要挣这个钱啊
Don't you have a pension?
你没退休金啊
Isn't your brother-in-law supporting you?
姐夫不养你了
Did the family clinic close?
还是家里医馆倒闭了
It's not about the money, okay?
这不是钱的事 好吗
You're just bored.
你就是闲的
Finding the person is what matters.
人找着就行了
Dear.
姐
I support you!
我支持你啊
I think learning something
我觉得学点东西
is great.
挺好的
I'm not stopping her from learning.
我也没拦着她学东西吧
But she shouldn't lie
但是她不能说瞎话
and say she went back home.
说她回老家了
I didn't lie to you.
我没骗你
Did you go back?
那你回了吗
That day I...
那天我
I had my luggage ready,
我就是提着行李
I was already at the bus station.
都到了汽车站了
I don't want to see your brother-in-law.
我就不想回去见你姐夫
So, I thought
我就想
I'd go to the hospital
到医院
to see my old classmate.
见一下我那老同学
Is it Xiao Song
是不是小宋
that told you that I'm here.
告诉你们我在这儿
Mr. Ouyang thought
欧阳哥以为
you were still at our place.
你还在我们家
We thought you went
那我们以为你呢
back to your hometown.
你回了老家了
Turns out
搞了半天
you were wandering outside all along.
原来你是在外面乱溜达
You're not going home?
你 你不回家
What's with all the Mr. Ouyang this, and that?
什么欧阳哥 欧阳哥的
He's your brother-in-law.
他就是你姐夫
Stop calling him.
以后你不用给他打电话
Then why didn't you answer my calls?
那你倒是接我电话呢
Wasn't I in class?
那我这不是上课呢吗
Do you
你上课
never have a break?
你没有下课的时候啊
Alright, alright, alright.
行了 行了 行了
If there's to say, we can talk at home.
有什么事回家说呗
Dear.
姐
Where's your luggage?
你行李在哪儿呢
Let's grab it and go home.
咱拿上 回呀
Well, I, I, I...
那个 我我我
This training institution...
这个培训机构
they provide accommodation.
人家管住宿
You don't need to worry about me.
你们不用操我的心了
Sis,
姐
whatever you want to do,
你想干什么
we won't stop you.
我们都不拦着你
But one thing,
但是有一样
you have to come home.
你得回家住
Mom, look!
妈妈 你看
I have rings all over my hands.
我满手的戒指
Look at the house I built, it's so pretty!
我搭的房子多漂亮啊
When I grow up,
长大以后
I want to be an architect.
我要当一个建筑师
Great!
好嘞
I want to sell rings.
我要卖戒指
That's awesome!
太棒了
Time to eat!
吃饭了啊
Okay.
好
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
Here's a little life hack,
一个生活小窍门
to share with you.
跟你分享
Hang a few men's clothes,
阳台上面
on the balcony.
挂几件男士衣服
It can prevent
可以防止一些
unnecessary trouble.
不必要的麻烦
If you don't have any,
你如果没有的话
I can lend you some.
我可以借给你
Mom, why are you laughing?
妈妈 你笑什么
Yeah.
对啊
Mom suddenly
妈妈突然
thought of something funny.
想起一件很好玩的事
What is it?
什么事啊
Then you share
那你们跟妈妈也分享
something interesting.
一个好玩的事
Okay.
好
Today we
我们今天
went to visit the museum.
去参观博物馆了
Yeah.
对啊
We saw it
我们看见了
a huge T-Rex.
大大的霸王龙
How big?
多大呀
As tall as a house!
有一个房子那么高呢
Yes.
对
That big?
那么大呀
what are you
那你们俩
to mommy?
是妈妈的什么呀
We are mommy's of
我们是妈妈的
little dinosaur babies.
小恐龙宝宝
Little twin dinosaur babies.
小双胞胎恐龙宝宝
Eat up.
快吃
You... you're leaving?
你 你 你这是要走啊
The client went into early labor.
约我那家提前生了
I need to hurry to accompany them.
我这得赶着去陪床啊
That's great!
太好了
Alright, alright.
好 好
I'm off.
走了啊
Goodbye, goodbye.
再见 再见
The room is too messy.
那个 屋里太乱了
You guys wait here.
你们在这儿等我
It's fine.
没事
I'll help you tidy up.
我帮你收拾
Xiao Wang,
小王
Jing, come eat something.
静姐 来吃点不
No, thanks.
不吃了
Who's this?
这人是谁啊
This is my sister-in-law.
这个是我弟妹
She came to pick me up.
来接我回家的
She is so nice.
弟妹真好
Let me help you.
我帮你
No, no, no need.
不用 不用 不用
Just stand there and wait for me.
你就站着 等我
Come on, come on.
来来来
Don't move, don't move.
你别动 你别动
Okay.
好
Take the bedding too.
被子褥子也带走吧
Li Lin,
李临
Is there space in the trunk?
后备箱有地方吗
Forget it.
不带了吧
There's no room at home either.
家里也放不下
Don't take it.
不要了
It's still new.
这还是新买的呢
Just listen.
你听话吧
Xiao Wang,
小王
Here,
这个
the bedding is for you.
被子褥子 送给你了
Li Lin,
李临
Thank you, Ms. Jing.
多谢静姐了
Come, get your luggage.
来 拿行李了
Your family is really nice.
你们家人真好
I'll do it.
我来
Have I caused a huge trouble?
我是惹了可大的祸吗
It's not a big deal.
事不大
But he's really angry.
但他是真生气了
Hurry up and leave.
快走吧
Ms. Jing, take care.
静姐 慢走啊
Okay, goodbye.
好 再见
Bye-bye.
拜拜